Guide to the Jean Marburg League of Women Voters collection, 1970-1988
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Jean Marburg League of Women Voters collection
1970-1988
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Marburg, Jean
C0039
13.25 linear feet (26 boxes)
Materials relate to the daily operations and special projects of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area (LWVFA), particularly 1979-1984 when Jean Marburg served on the Executive Board. Materials are representative of LWVFA's focus on many community, social, environmental, and political issues such as nuclear energy, hunger, defense, international development, and trade. Types of materials include reports, correspondence, printed materials, and notes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Jean Marburg in 1995.
Biographical Information
Jean Marburg served as a member of the Executive Board of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area from 1979-1984.
Scope and Content
Materials relate to the daily operations and special projects of the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area (LWVFA), particularly 1979-1984 when Jean Marburg served on the Executive Board. Materials are representative of LWVFA's focus on many community, social, environmental, and political issues such as nuclear energy, hunger, defense, international development and trade. Types of materials include reports, correspondence, printed materials, and notes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area records.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area.
Geographical Names:
Fairfax Region (Va.)--Politics and government.
Subjects:
Citizens' associations--Virginia--Fairfax Region.; Political participation--Virginia--Fairfax Region.
Contents List
- Jean Marburg League of Women Voters collection
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Great Decisions (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - 1985 (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - LWVFA Board 1980 (Folder 5, Box 2)
  - LWVFA - BD 1980 (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - LWV VA Board (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - LWV VA Board Meeting (Folder 8, Box 2)
  - LWV VA Board 79 - 80 (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - LWV VA - BD, 1980 (Folder 10, Box 2)
  - League of Women Voters State Board 1980 (Folder 11, Box 2)
  - LWV VA - State REF, BD '81 Voters (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - LWV VA - Board Meeting June 1 - 2, 1980 (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - League of Women Voters 1982 - 83 Board 1983 (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - LWV VA Board Meeting July 1984 (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - LWV VA Board Meeting 9/14/84 also 81 - 84 (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - LWV VA - Board Meeting, NOV 1984 (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - LWV VA Board Notes Ref 85 (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - League of Women Voters Virginia 1980 (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - League of Women Voters of Virginia - State Council April 23, 24, 1980 (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Virginia League of Women Voters July 1980 (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - Virginia League of Women Voters Dec 1980 (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Virginia League of Women Voters (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters July 1983 (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters July 1984 (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - Virginia league of Women Voters July 1980 (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - UN Conference on Development 9/84 (Folder 10, Box 4)
  - Interview with Senator Warner 2-22-1985 (Folder 11, Box 4)
  - League of Women Voters National Capital Area (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters National Capital Area (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - Correspondence/Titles/Clippings (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - National Security Item LWV US - Convention - 1980 (Folder 5, Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters Misc (Folder 6, Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 7, Box 5)
  - Overseas Education Fund - 1980 (Folder 1, Box 6)
  - LWV US - MINI Conf. - Aug 21 - 22, 1980 (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters Misc (Folder 3, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters Misc - 1981 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - Food Stamps 6/81 (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters US - Voting Rights Act (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters United States National Program 1982 (Folder 7, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 8, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 9, Box 6)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 1, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 2, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Lobby Corps 1982 (Folder 3, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 4, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Lobby Corps 1982 (Folder 5, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Senator John Warner (Folder 6, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 7, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Budget 1983 (Folder 8, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Misc - Pamphlets 1983 (Folder 9, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters Lobby Corps 1983 (Folder 10, Box 7)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 11, Box 7)
  - Lobby Corps 1978 - 79 (Folder 1, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1979 (Folder 2, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1979 (Folder 3, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1979 (Folder 4, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1979 (Folder 5, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1979 (Folder 6, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps 1980 (Folder 7, Box 8)
  - Lobby Corps Background 1980 (Folder 1, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps Background 1980 (Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps Background 1980 (Folder 3, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps Background 1980 (Folder 4, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps Nov/Dec 1980 (Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Lobbying - Workshop (Folder 6, Box 9)
  - Clean Air Act - 3/81 (Folder 7, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps -1981 (Folder 8, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps -1981 (Folder 9, Box 9)
  - Lobby Corps -Feb 1981 (Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps - 1981 (Folder 2, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps - 1982 (Folder 3, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps - 1983 Acid Rain (Folder 4, Box 10)
  - ERA (Folder 5, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps - 9/27/83 ERA Lobbying (Folder 6, Box 10)
  - Domestic Content Legis. HR 1234, April '83 (Folder 7, Box 10)
  - "Get Acquainted" 1983 (Folder 8, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps - Job Bill (#1036) 9/83 (Folder 9, Box 10)
  - Clean Water - Mar '83 (Folder 10, Box 10)
  - HR 5490 - Civil Rights Act '84 (Folder 11, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps Misc (Folder 12, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps '83 (Folder 13, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps Feb '83 (Folder 14, Box 10)
  - Lobby Corps Feb 1983 (Folder 15, Box 10)
  - Lobbying Clear Water June '84 (Folder 1, Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 2, Box 11)
  - Lobby Corps '85 (Folder 3, Box 11)
  - Lobby Corps '85 (Folder 4, Box 11)
  - Lobbying (Folder 5, Box 11)
  - Lobbying (Folder 6, Box 11)
  - Energy Sept 1979 (Folder 7, Box 11)
  - Energy Sept 1979 (Folder 8, Box 11)
  - Energy Sept 1980 (Folder 9, Box 11)
  - Energy Sept 1980 (Folder 10, Box 11)
  - Energy (Folder 1, Box 12)
  - Great Decisions 1982 (Folder 2, Box 12)
  - Food - Hunger 1980 - 81 (Folder 3, Box 12)
  - World Hunger background Material (Folder 4, Box 12)
  - World Hunger (Folder 5, Box 12)
  - World Hunger 11/19/81 (Folder 6, Box 12)
  - World Hunger Recent Info 1981 (Folder 7, Box 12)
  - World Hunger - Discussion of Resources (Folder 8, Box 12)
  - World Hunger (Folder 9, Box 12)
  - World Hunger (Folder 10, Box 12)
  - World Hunger 1981 (Folder 1, Box 13)
  - APR 1970 China, Aid (Folder 2, Box 13)
  - Conference for Women on Salt Two Dec 5, 1978 (Folder 3, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 4, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters IR (Folder 5, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area IR (Folder 6, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters IR 1980 (Folder 7, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters IR 1980 (Folder 8, Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters IR 1980 (Folder 9, Box 13)
  - International Services Available to West Virginia Business (Folder 1, Box 14)
  - International Relations 1981 - 82 (Folder 2, Box 14)
  - Nuclear Arms 1981 - 82 (Folder 3, Box 14)
  - Nuclear Arms (Folder 4, Box 14)
  - General 1981 - 82 (Folder 5, Box 14)
  - League of Women Voters IR (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 7, Box 14)
  - Fairfax Area International Relations (Folder 1, Box 15)
  - League Women Voters of the Fairfax Area International Relations (Folder 2, Box 15)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area - IR (Folder 3, Box 15)
  - EL Salvador (Folder 4, Box 15)
  - to File 1/6/82 (Folder 5, Box 15)
  - Meeting 2/26/82 Nuclear Arms (Folder 6, Box 15)
  - Environment for Humanity Conference 3/17 - 18/82 (Folder 7, Box 15)
  - World Federalists Association 3/82 (Folder 8, Box 15)
  - talkout Materials 3/82 (Folder 9, Box 15)
  - International Relations Misc 1982 (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - International Relations Misc (Folder 1, Box 16)
  - Ground Zero Materials (envelop only) 3/82 (Folder 2, Box 16)
  - World Hunger Reports of Unit Disc (Folder 3, Box 16)
  - Agenda Board (Folder 5, Box 16)
  - League of Women Voters Fairfax Area - IR (Folder 6, Box 16)
  - Elected Clippings (Folder 7, Box 16)
  - International Relations Misc (Folder 8, Box 16)
  - News clippings (Folder 9, Box 16)
  - Nuclear Issues (Folder 1, Box 17)
  - Nuclear Issues News clippings 1982 (Folder 2, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters of the Fairfax Area International Relations 1983 (Folder 3, Box 17)
  - League of Women voters Fairfax Area - IR 1983 (Folder 4, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters IR (Folder 5, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters IR (Folder 6, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters IR - 1983 - 85 (Folder 7, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters IR (Folder 8, Box 17)
  - League of Women Voters IR 1984 - 85 (Folder 9, Box 17)
  - International Relations 1986 (Folder 10, Box 17)
  - International Relations 1988 (Folder 11, Box 17)
  - Articles (Folder 12, Box 17)
  - National Security (Folder 1, Box 18)
  - National Security (Folder 2, Box 18)
  - National Security (Folder 3, Box 18)
  - National Security (Folder 4, Box 18)
  - National Security VA Voters Attitude (Folder 5, Box 18)
  - A Military Policy Reader Draft (Folder 6, Box 18)
  - National Security LWV Documents (Folder 7, Box 18)
  - UN - League Day 1982 - 83 (Folder 8, Box 18)
  - National Security 1982 - 83 (Folder 9, Box 18)
  - LWV - US National Security 1982 - 83 (Folder 10, Box 18)
  - National Security LWV Us 1982 - 83 (Folder 11, Box 18)
  - LWV VA - National Security Feb And Mar 1983 (Folder 1, Box 19)
  - National Security 1983 (Folder 2, Box 19)
  - National Security 1983 (Folder 3, Box 19)
  - 1983 (Folder 4, Box 19)
  - 1982 - 84 (Folder 5, Box 19)
  - NNSS - Agenda Item 1 (Folder 6, Box 19)
  - NNSS - Agenda Item 3 (Folder 7, Box 19)
  - NNSS Agendas Item #4 (Folder 8, Box 19)
  - 1984 (Folder 9, Box 19)
  - National Security Conference 1984 (Folder 10, Box 19)
  - National Security (Folder 11, Box 19)
  - National Security (Folder 12, Box 19)
  - National Security 1 of 2 (Folder 1, Box 20)
  - National Security 2 of 2 (Folder 2, Box 20)
  - National Security Arms Control 1 of 2 1983 - 89 (Folder 3, Box 20)
  - National Security Arms Control 2 of 2 1983 - 89 (Folder 4, Box 20)
  - Star Wars - Oct 84 (Folder 5, Box 20)
  - Star Wars - Oct 85 - 86 (Folder 6, Box 20)
  - Star Wars - Oct 85 - 89 (Folder 7, Box 20)
  - Star Wars - 88 (Folder 1, Box 21)
  - Star Wars (Folder 2, Box 21)
  - Star Wars (Folder 3, Box 21)
  - Star Wars (Folder 4, Box 21)
  - WNDC - Lectures Fall ' 84 (Folder 1, Box 22)
  - 1981 (Folder 2, Box 22)
  - 1985 (Folder 3, Box 22)
  - Women (Folder 4, Box 22)
  - Clippings from pat Gensen, McClean VA LWV 1981 (Folder 5, Box 22)
  - Conflict Resolution (Folder 6, Box 22)
  - Congress (Folder 7, Box 22)
  - 1980 Convention (Folder 8, Box 22)
  - Environment (Folder 2, Box 22)
  - ERA (Folder 10, Box 22)
  - Food Background Material (Folder 11, Box 22)
  - Health Care (Folder 12, Box 22)
  - Low Cost Housing (Folder 13, Box 22)
  - LL's Summer, 1983 (Folder 14, Box 22)
  - League of Women Voters Publications (Folder 15, Box 22)
  - National Security (Folder 16, Box 22)
  - Voting (Folder 17, Box 22)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 1, Box 23)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 2, Box 23)
  - League of Women Voters Trade (Folder 3, Box 23)
  - League of Women Voters (Folder 4, Box 23)
  - League of Women Voters Trade (Folder 3, Box 23)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 24)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 25)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 26)